Guide to the Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement Collection, 1946-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement collection 1946-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China
3.5 linear feet Extent: 1758 Items
Produced mostly by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China. The material was found in a cinema company office in Henan province, China. Collection of film advertisements and transcripts of Chinese documentary films and newsreels that spans the years 1946 to 1985; bulk of items are transcripts for documentary films and newsreels from the Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976. Dating of the 1946 item is questionable. All documents are in Chinese. Arranged into the following series: Advertisements and Film Description Series; Documentary and Newsreel Scripts Series; Feature Filmscripts Series; and Newspaper Clipping Scrapbook Series. Topics include industry, agriculture, the economy, military matters, education, public health care, medicine and science, as well as political movements, foreign relations, cultural and sporting events. Collection also contains a group of printed advertisements and other publicity for Chinese and foreign films, plays, opera, and local performances. Finally, collection includes 8 master microfilm reels for the collection.
RL.00223
Language: Material in Chinese
Administrative Information
Online Items
The Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement Collection is available to the Duke University community in digital format via IDC Publishers Primary Sources Online: http://www.primarysourcesonline.nl/c22/. Access to this digital collection requires the DjVu Browser Plug-in by LizardTech.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2005.
Historical Note
Produced mostly by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China, documentary films and newsreels were two of the major mass media and communication channels in China from the 1950s through 1970s. They covered all aspects of social activities, though the emphasis was on developments and achievements in the building of a socialist country. In order to reach even broader public audiences, government agents produced and printed the transcripts and shot lists for the films and sent them to cities and rural areas. Few of these printed materials have survived due to the poor quality of the paper upon which they were printed. The material in this collection was found in a cinema company office in Henan province, China.
Collection Overview
The collection of film advertisements and transcripts of Chinese documentary films and newsreels spans the years 1946 to 1985, although the bulk of the items in the collection are transcripts for the documentary films and newsreels from the Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976. It should also be noted that the dating of the 1946 item is questionable. All documents in the collection are in Chinese. The collection is arranged into the following series: Advertisements and Film Description Series, 1953-1966 and undated; Documentary and Newsreel Scripts Series, 1946 (?)-1985 and undated; Feature Filmscripts Series, undated; and Newspaper Clipping Scrapbook Series, 1950-1959 and undated. Topics include industry, agriculture, the economy, military matters, education, public health care, medicine and science, as well as political movements, foreign relations, cultural and sporting events. Most of the documentary filmscripts are short, focusing on a specific subject or event, whereas newsreel scripts are numbered sequentially within each year and cover multiple topics or events. During the Cultural Revolution, documentary films and newsreels were powerful and popular propaganda tools for patriotism, nationalism, Chairman Mao, the Communist Party, and socialist construction, and served political purposes.
In this collection, there is also a group of printed advertisements and other publicity for Chinese and foreign films, plays, opera, and local performances. This collection is valuable for studies of contemporary Chinese culture, the Cultural Revolution, history and politics, communist propaganda, and mass media.
The collection was microfilmed for broader access in 2006, and the original master copies of the microfilm are in the final box of the collection.
Subject Headings
China -- History -- 1949-1976; China -- History -- 1949-1976 -- Sources; China -- History -- Cultural Revolution -- 1966-1976; China -- Politics and government -- 1949-1976; Documentary films -- China -- History and criticism; Propaganda, Communist -- China; Mass media -- China; Communication -- Political aspects -- China; Communication in politics -- China
Contents of Collection
- Advertisements and Film Description Series, 1953-1966 and undated, 1 box
  Film advertisements and publicity materials for Chinese documentary films, Chinese feature films, and foreign films that were imported mostly from communist countries, such as Vietnam, North Korea, Romania, and Albania. They include summaries of the story, main characters, publicity topics, terms of use, text for blackboard postings or broadcasting, and discussion questions. Also includes some posters, performance schedules and programs for films, plays, opera, local performances, etc. Some of these have illustrations and screen shots. Arranged by title, then chronologically.
  - 宣 传 资 料 Xuan Chuan Zi Liao, 1953-1966 and undated, (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - 宣 传 资 料 Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 银 屏 花 絮 Yin Ping Hua Xu, No.3, 7-10, and 60, (1 folder)
  - 电 影 介 绍 Dian Ying Jie Shao, No. 7706-7707, 7801-7923, 7901,and 7908-7909, (1 folder)
- Documentary and Newsreel Scripts Series, 1946(?)-1985 and undated, 3 boxes
  Transcripts and shot lists for newsreels and documentary films. These focus on specific subjects, events or personal stories. Scripts in boxes 2 and 3 are arranged by subject, then chronologically within each subject. The date on the earliest item in box 3 is questionable. There are also a few special issues. For example, a special issue in February 1966 is entitled: Chairman Mao’s Good Student- Jiao Yulu. Scripts for Xin Wen Jian Bao in box 4 are arranged by number and year.
  - 政 沸 Politics; 1958-1978 and undated, (7 folders) (Box 2)
  - 外 交 Foreign Relations; 1961-1977 and undated, (6 folders)
  - 军 事 Military; 1964-1966, 1976-1984 and undated, (4 folders)
  - 工 业 Industry, 1959-1978 and undated, (6 folders) (Box 3)
  - 农 业 Agriculture, 1960-1978 and undated; 1973-1975, (7 folders)
  - 文 化 Culture, 1960-1985 and undated, (2 folders)
  - 教 育 Education, 1946(?)-1976, (1 folder)
  - 体 育 Sports, 1960 -1975 and undated, (1 folder)
  - 卫 生, 医 疗 和 科 学 Health, Medicine, and Science, 1960-1977, (1 folder)
  - 新 闻 简 报 Xin Wen Jian Bao, No.1-19; No.29-41; 1965-1969; and 1971-1977, (15 folders) (Box 4)
- Feature Filmscripts Series, undated, 1 box
  Filmscripts for 12 Chinese and foreign feature films.
  - 外 国 电 影 Foreign Films, B-K, L-S, Y-Z, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - 中 国 电 影 Chinese Films, B-D, F-L, Q-S, W-Z, and Miscellaneous, (9 folders)
- Newspaper Clipping Scrapbook Series, 1950-1959 and undated, 1 box
  Scrapbook containing film reviews (many on foreign films), publicity material, articles on film production and distribution, and reports on film conferences, festivals, and award ceremonies.
  - 报 刊 剪 辑 Newspaper clips, (1 scrapbook of clips) (Box 6)
- Microfilm Master Reels, (1 box)
  8 silver duplicate microfilm reels of the collection.
  - Microfilm reels (8 reels) (Box 7)